SAI MEGHANA KOMPALLI (1) Featured

System Engineer seeking roles in Software Development,UI Development,Application Support ,Project Management,Change Management,Defect Management,Quality Management, Requirement



Gathering, JavaScript, React, Redux, Router, HTML, CSS, AJAX

Current Designation: System Engineer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Current Company: TCS Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: React.Js,Redux,React Router,Javascript,JQuery,HTML,CSS,Html5,Responsive Web Design,UI

Development, Ajax, JSON, CSS3, Adobe Experience Manager, Cq5, NPM

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Front-end developer with 2.5+ years of experience in building high performing presentation layers. Built reusable components, performance optimization, and specific focus on using React library in doing projects along with different POC handled as an agile model.

Work Experience

TCS as System Engineer Mar 2017 to Till Date

Working as UI developer in TCS

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. as Systems Engineer -Software Development Mar 2017 to Mar 2017

Project Client: Thomson Reuters 10/17 Till date

Project 1 OpenWeb E-Stores

Open web is an Ecommerce platform which maintains Ecommerce sites like Thomson Reuters Spain, Australia and Argentina. The content of the sites will be managed through Adobe Experience Manager and the back end is hybris. Project 2 Migration and Upgrade (AEM 6.2 to AEM 6.4)

As Technology keep on upgrading from different versions an upgrade project is created to enhance the E-Store performance. As OpenWeb E-Store is a huge content and involved with many components and complex functionalities logics this was handled as a separate project

RESPONIBILITIES

Involved in development activities in UI perspective and responsible for creating javascript modules in our project.

Developed new UI functionality for multithreaded user-facing applications using ReactJS and React-router.

Designed and developed various Web pages using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, ReactJS

Involved in creating project structure and development of templates and page components.

Handled complex state management situations using the Redux library.

Developed custom responsive reusable components using ReactJS.

Built single-page applications with JavaScript on a custom-built framework.

Responsible for checking cross-browser compatibility and hence worked on different browsers like Safari,

Firefox, Google Chrome, and Internet Explorer.

Good experience in debugging JavaScript, CSS3, and HTML5 code.

Developed AEM custom components, dialogs, design dialogs, custom client libraries.

Involved in the development of AEM templates and page components.

Involved in AEM 6.2 to 6.4 migration and upgrade (Classic UI to TouchUI).

Involved in React and AEM training activities for freshers.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from PVP Siddhartha institute of Technology, Vijayawada in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
REACT	16 & above	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Redux	7 & above	2020	1 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
Routing	4 & above	2020	2 Year(s)	
JavaScript	ES- 6,ES+	2020	2 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
HTML	5	2020	2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
CSS	3	2020	2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
AEM	6.2 & 6.4	2020	2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
NPM	6 & above	2020	1 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Proficient			
Telugu	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: AEM Migration and Upgrade

Client: ThomsonReuters

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2018 - Jun 2019 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: hyderabad

Role: Programmer Team Size: 3 Skill Used: Adobe Experience Manager, slightly, Html5, CSS, Javascript, Ajax, JSON, Role Description: Front end UI Developer, custom dialogs and design developer

Project Details: As Technology keep on upgrading from different versions an upgrade project is created to enhance the Estore performance. As Openweb E-store is a huge content and involved with many components and complex functionalities logics this was handled as separate project

Project Title: Openweb E-store Client: ThomsonReuters

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2017 - Till Date Project Location: hyderabad Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 3 Role: Programmer

Skill Used: React, Redux, React-router, JSX, Html5, CSS3, Javascript (ES-6), Adobe Experience Manager, Sightly, Ajax, JSON

Role Description: Front end UI developer

Project Details: Openweb is a E-store platform which maintains Ecommerce sites like ThomsonReuters

Spain, Australia, Argentina. The content of the sites will be managed through Adobe Experience Manager and the back end is

hybris.

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time